Ibrahim Kalam

Details

London, N16, England 07881023696 ikalam869@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Portfolio Website

Skills

Python

HTML5 CSS3

JavaScript, TypeScript

React JS

SQL

Solidity

Ethereum

Research and Problem Solving

Fluency in using scientific equipment

Refined mathematical skills

Modeling and simulation

Quality control

Profile

Physics graduate with over two years of experience in web development and software engineering, attaining most principles from online courses. Demonstrated ability to develop and implement programs in various technologies including HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React. Experienced in debugging and optimizing code, developing user-friendly interfaces and solving complex problems.

Employment History

Quality Assurance Manager at Legal Utopia, London

Остовек 2021 — Мау 2022

- Led and directed the quality assurance department, successfully implementing and maintaining the Legal Utopia quality management system.
- Actively managed a team which overlooked assets released by the company, duly ensuring
 work is completed to a high standard such that they align with brand identity.
- Improved synergy across departments where the opportunity to learn the fundamentals of front-end development was seized.

Lifeguard at Virgin Active, London

June 2016 — October 2017

- Attentively cared for the safety of customers by proactively communicating with staff and customers.
- Regulated the chemical levels of the pool while keeping the vicinity well sanitized.
- Demonstrated proficiency in CPR/AED and First Aid certification.

Education

Physics, University of Bath, Bath

- For my final year project I compared methods for EEG source localization.
- Developed a program to localize the source of electromagnetic waves within the brain from raw EEG scans.
- Investigated and implemented various source localization algorithms and compared results using MATLAB.

Latymer Grammar School, London

SEPTEMBER 2015 — JUNE 2017

AAB in A-level subjects: Maths, Physics and Economics, respectively.

Internships

Structural Engineer at Heyne Tillett Steel, London

JULY 2015 — AUGUST 2015

- · Evaluated and designed residential infrastructures with applied engineering principles.
- Performed structural stability calculations and sketched support drawings prior to construction.